Narrator: 1
Speaker: This beautiful elephant is an example of Dhokra metal art,
which originated in India over four thousand years ago.
The technique involves carving a figure out of wax, covering this with clay,
baking the clay until the wax melts, and then filling the hollow clay with liquid metal.
Narrator: 2
Speaker: Archaeologists have discovered over a hundred thousand different pieces of ancient Greek pottery,
all of which date back to the first millennium B.C.
Much of it was produced locally for everyday and kitchen use,
but the finer pieces were intended purely for decoration.
Narrator: 3
Speaker: This necklace, known as a broad collar,
would probably have been worn by an Egyptian pharaoh,
or placed around the neck of a statue. Broad collars were made of metal,
and typically consisted of rows of beads, made out of gold, glass, or gemstones.
Narrator: 4
Speaker: This helmet, or galea, is typical of the ones worn by soldiers of the Roman Empire.
It has a bowl to protect the skull, a large neck guard,
a band to protect the forehead, and cheek plates to protect the face.